What if the path through the wall was visible? Not the jobs — the wall.
Five offices, forty-seven forms, a bus that takes seventy-one minutes.
GoWork is a workforce navigator. It maps the wall — every barrier
between a worker and a paycheck — and routes them around it.
We're going to walk through one resident's twelve weeks in Fort Worth.
Carlos is twenty-nine. A father of one. Four years of warehouse work.
He has three hundred dollars and no car. He is ready to work.
This is The Wall.
Fort Worth, Texas. Carlos lives east of downtown. ZIP 76119.
Trinity Metro routes thread the city — half don't reach the warehouses.
Single father of one daughter, four years old. Three years past a
misdemeanor — sentence complete. Forklift certified. Four barriers.
Most workforce sites pretend barriers don't matter. We do the math.
Criminal record: 71-minute commute. No childcare: $1,200 a month.
Bad credit: 540 score, one in three jobs unreachable.
Five offices. Forty-seven forms. Each one says go to the next one.
Without GoWork, this is the path. We named it so we could replace it.
When more pay means less money. A two-dollar raise sounds like a win.
Childcare subsidy gone at $14/hr. SNAP gone at $17/hr.
Five stops. Twelve weeks. One plan. Home to DPS to HHSC to Legal Aid
to Workforce Solutions. Trinity Metro Bus 4 and Bus 6 carry him.
The wall isn't a list. It's a graph. Thirty-three nodes. Seven
categories. Resolve one barrier and three others move within reach.
It works in Fort Worth. It will work in Montgomery. It will work
where you are. Two cities deployed. Six on deck. Same engine.
You've seen the wall. You've seen the labyrinth. Now skip both —
start your assessment.
GoWork is open-source under MIT. Fort Worth is the reference
deployment. Montgomery is the second. Built for HackFW 2026.